Left and right work pretty well in specific circumstances.
العمل اليسار واليمين بشكل جيد جدًا في ظروف محددة.
When the data is structured very cleanly with a certain number of characters.
عندما يتم هيكلة البيانات بشكل نظيف جدًا مع عدد معين من الأحرف
If you want a separate city and state,
إذا كنت ترغب في مدينة أو دولة منفصلة،
you've got to do a little more work.
فعليك القيام بمزيد من العمل.
The first thing that will be helpful is figuring out
أول شيء سيكون مفيدًا هو معرفة
exactly where the city and state split.
مكان تقسيم المدينة والدولة بالضبط.
Since it will be different for each row,
وبما أنه سيكون مختلفًا لكل صف،
we have to use a function that will find
فعلينا استخدام الدالة التي ستعثر على
the comma and identify how far into the record it is.
الفاصلة وتحديد مدى بعدها في السجل.
Position allows you to specify a sub-string,
يتيح لك الموضع تحديد سلسلة فرعية،
then it returns a numerical value equal to
ثم إرجاع قيمة عددية تساوي
how far away from the left that particular character appears.
بعد المسافة عن اليسار الذي يظهر فيه هذا الحرف.
You can also use the string position function which is
يمكنك أيضًا استخدام دالة وضع السلسلة التي
annotated as as STRPOS to achieve the same results.
توضح بكونها STRPOS لتحقيق النتائج نفسها.
Just replace in with a comma and switch the order of the string and the sub-string.
ما عليك سوى استبدال الفاصلة وتبديل ترتيب السلسلة والسلسلة الفرعية.
Importantly, both the position and string position functions are case sensitive.
والأهم من ذلك، أن كل من دالتي الموضع ووضع السلسلة حساسة لحالة الأحرف.
If you want to look for a character regardless of its case,
إذا كنت تريد البحث عن حرف بغض النظر عن حالته،
you can make the entire string upper or lower case.
فيمكنك جعل السلسلة بأكملها من الحروف الكبيرة أو الصغيرة.
You can use lower to force every character in a string to become lowercase.
يمكنك استخدام lower لجعل جميع أحرف الأحرف في السلسلة صغيرة.
Similarly, you can use UPPER to make all the letters appear as uppercase.
وبالمثل، يمكنك استخدام UPPER لجعل جميع أحرف الأحرف في السلسلة كبيرة.
Let's complete the loop and pull just the city out into its own field.
دعونا نكمل الحلقة ونسحب المدينة فقط إلى مجالها الخاص.
We can do this by nesting the position inside a Left function.
يمكننا القيام بذلك عن طريق إنزال الموضع ضمن دالة اليسار.
As you can see, what we really want isn't the full text up to the position of the comma,
كما ترى، ما نريده حقًا ليس النص الكامل حتى موضع الفاصلة،
we want to end one position before
نريد إنهاء موضع واحد قبل
the comma so that it's not included in our city column.
الفاصلة بحيث لا يتم تضمينه في عمود المدينة.
We can do this by subtracting one within the left function.
يمكننا القيام بذلك عن طريق طرح واحد ضمن دالة اليسرى.